Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about something that has always been very
我是Catherine，今天我们要聊一个对我来说一直很
confusing for me.
让人困惑的话题。
For me as well.
我也是。
I don't understand very well what this is about.
我不太明白这到底是怎么回事。
We're going to be talking about time zones and a little bit about daylight savings time.
我们要讨论的是时区，还有一点夏令时。
Before we get started though, let's take a look at this phrase in today's vocabulary
不过在我们开始之前，先来看看今天词汇预览中的这个短语。
preview.
词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
All right, so the phrase is daylight savings time.
好的，这个短语是“夏令时”。
Okay, so we're trying to save daylight pretty much.
嗯，所以我们基本上是在试图“节省”日光。
That's right.
没错。
So this is the time of year when we change our clocks.
这是一年中我们调整时钟的时间。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
That means in the fall there's a special day and everyone has it on their calendar and
意思是秋天有一个特殊的日子，每个人都在日历上标记了，
we change the clocks.
然后我们调整时钟。
We put them back one hour.
我们把时钟拨慢一小时。
So if it was eight o'clock now it's seven o'clock.
所以如果现在是八点，就变成七点。
Okay, so everything is earlier, starts earlier.
好的，所以一切都提前了，开始得更早了。
And that's basically to take advantage of the daylight, right?
这基本上是为了利用日光，对吧？
That's why it's called daylight savings time.
这就是为什么它叫“夏令时”。
Exactly.
正是。
And so that's for the winter and then when the winter's past we change the clocks again.
所以这是为了冬天，然后冬天过去后，我们再次调整时钟。
We have the spring daylight savings where we change our clocks ahead.
我们有春季夏令时，那时我们把时钟拨快。
Okay.
好的。
So it sounds kind of complicated.
听起来有点复杂。
Many countries don't have daylight savings time.
很多国家没有夏令时。
They don't change their clocks at all.
他们根本不调整时钟。
But we're going to be talking about this in a little bit more so why don't we listen to
但我们还会再详细讨论这个，所以不如我们先听一遍
our dialogue for the first time.
我们的对话。
Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time?
你为了夏令时把时钟拨快了吗？
What?
什么？
Why do we have to do that?
我们为什么要这么做？
Well, at the start of the spring we usually have more daylight in the mornings and less
嗯，在春天开始的时候，我们通常早上有更多日光，下午
in the afternoon.
更少。
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the Earth.
这基本上是由于我们在地球上的位置和地球的自转。
In any case, to take better advantage of the daylight available we compensate by moving
无论如何，为了更好地利用可用的日光，我们通过把
our clocks forward one hour.
时钟拨快一小时来补偿。
I see.
我明白了。
That's convenient.
那很方便。
I never understood things like this such as GMT.
我从来不懂像GMT这样的东西。
I never know what time zone we are in or when to change my clock.
我从来不知道我们在哪个时区，或者什么时候调整时钟。
That just stands for Greenwich Mean Time.
那代表格林威治标准时间。
Here in California we're in Pacific Standard Time.
在加州这里，我们处于太平洋标准时间。
That is eight time zones west of Greenwich.
那是格林威治以西八个时区。
Remember when we were in Beijing?
还记得我们在北京的时候吗？
Well, then we were in China Standard Time and that's eight time zones east of Greenwich.
嗯，那时我们处于中国标准时间，那是格林威治以东八个时区。
That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA because of the huge time difference.
这就是为什么从北京飞到洛杉矶那么奇怪，因为时差很大。
Even though we left Beijing at noon and flew for more than eight hours, we still arrived
尽管我们中午离开北京，飞了八个多小时，我们还是
in LA the same day at noon.
在同一天中午到达洛杉矶。
It's like we went back in time.
就像我们回到了过去。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So that was a pretty clear explanation of why we do these things.
所以那是对我们为什么做这些事的一个相当清晰的解释。
But maybe there are a couple of words that you didn't understand.
但可能有一些词你没听懂。
So let's take a look at those now in Language Takeaway.
所以现在让我们在“语言要点”中看看这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, Marco, what you were hinting at before, this idea that we have shorter days in the
嗯，Marco，你之前暗示的，冬天白天短、夏天白天长这个想法，
winter and longer days in the summer has to do with the rotation of the Earth.
与地球的自转有关。
So the rotation of the Earth is our first phrase.
所以“地球的自转”是我们的第一个短语。
So the Earth rotates.
所以地球在自转。
What does that mean if it rotates?
如果它自转，那是什么意思？
Means to spin around.
意思是旋转。
But not just to spin around anywhere.
但不是随便旋转。
It means that if you draw a line through the middle of something, it never leaves that
意思是如果你在某个物体中间画一条线，它永远不会离开那条
line.
线。
It just kind of turns.
它只是转动。
So it's spinning.
所以它在旋转。
Like the wheels on a car.
就像汽车的车轮。
They rotate.
它们旋转。
That means they go around but they are fixed to the car.
意思是它们转动，但固定在车上。
So this is one of the reasons why we need to compensate our clocks because of the rotation
所以这就是为什么我们需要补偿时钟的原因之一，因为地球
of the Earth.
的自转。
And that's our next word, to compensate.
那是我们的下一个词，“补偿”。
This is a verb, to compensate.
这是一个动词，“补偿”。
And it's often used with money but it can be used with time as well.
它通常和钱一起用，但也可以和时间一起用。
Time or sunlight.
时间或阳光。
So with money you'd say, I paid him a hundred dollars but I owed him a hundred fifty.
所以和钱一起用，你会说：我付了他一百美元，但我欠他一百五十。
So I'm going to compensate him for the extra fifty.
所以我要补偿他额外的五十。
Means I'm going to fix it.
意思是我要纠正它。
So to compensate would be the verb and compensation would be the noun.
所以，“compensate”是动词，“compensation”是名词。
Now in this case we're talking about time.
现在这里我们说的是时间。
So how can we compensate time?
那我们怎么补偿时间呢？
Well that means that if we have lost an hour because we changed the clocks, we have to
意思是，如果我们因为调钟而损失了一个小时，我们就得
compensate.
补偿。
We have to try and gain that hour back.
我们得想办法把那一个小时补回来。
And so that's why in the spring, after the days start to get longer and longer, we have
这就是为什么在春天，白天开始变得越来越长之后，我们得
to compensate for that by changing the clocks again.
再次调钟来补偿。
So we're compensating time.
所以我们是在补偿时间。
Now related to daylight savings and this whole time thing is time zones.
现在，与夏令时和整个时间相关的是时区。
We have time zones all over the Earth.
地球上到处都有时区。
And you've probably noticed this if you've traveled.
如果你旅行过，可能就注意到了。
You have to change your clocks or many times you see in hotels what time it is in London,
你得调钟，或者经常在酒店里看到伦敦、
in Hong Kong, in Berlin, etc.
香港、柏林等地的时间。
And this makes a lot of sense because like we said, the Earth is rotating and so if it's
这很有道理，因为就像我们说的，地球在自转，所以如果
daylight in Moscow and it's nighttime in New York, obviously it's not the same time.
莫斯科是白天，纽约是晚上，显然时间不一样。
So to compensate for this difference, we have different time zones.
为了补偿这种差异，我们有了不同的时区。
And each time zone is pretty much an hour or so, you know, half an hour different from
每个时区基本上相差一个小时左右，或者半小时，
the next one.
和下一个时区不同。
Right.
对。
So most countries actually have different time zones throughout their country unless
所以大多数国家内部都有不同的时区，除非
they're small that they don't really need to compensate any change.
国家很小，不需要补偿任何变化。
Or for example, China, just to unify everything, it's a big country but they have one time
或者比如中国，为了统一，它是个大国，但只有一个时
zone.
区。
It's China standard time.
就是中国标准时间。
Exactly.
没错。
But in the United States, we have four time zones.
但在美国，我们有四个时区。
Right.
对。
Alright.
好的。
So that's time zone.
这就是时区。
And the other thing related to time zone is time difference.
另一个与时区相关的是时差。
Okay, well think about math here.
好，我们来想想数学。
Difference is a word that we use in math.
“差”是数学里用的词。
And a time difference is the amount of time, that means how many hours there are between
时差就是时间量，意思是两个时区之间
one time zone and another time zone.
相差多少小时。
So for example, Beijing and New York City.
比如北京和纽约市。
These are very, very far away from each other.
这两个地方离得非常非常远。
If it's day in New York, it's night in Beijing.
如果纽约是白天，北京就是晚上。
So that means if it's seven in the morning in Beijing, it's probably around seven at
所以如果北京是早上七点，纽约大概就是
night in New York.
晚上七点。
So the time difference would be more or less 12 hours.
所以时差大约是12小时。
Exactly.
没错。
But when it's daylight savings time, it's 13.
但如果是夏令时，就是13小时。
So be careful.
所以要小心。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
I think that's pretty clear.
我觉得这很清楚。
I think we should go back and listen to our dialogue again.
我觉得我们应该回去再听一遍对话。
And we'll be back soon with Fluency Builder.
我们很快会回来，进行流利度训练。
Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time?
你为夏令时把钟调快了吗？
What?
什么？
Why do we have to do that?
我们为什么要这么做？
Well, at the start of the spring, we usually have more daylight in the mornings and less
嗯，在春天开始时，我们通常早上有更多日光，下午
in the afternoon.
更少。
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the earth.
这基本上是因为我们在地球上的位置和地球的自转。
In any case, to take better advantage of the daylight available, we compensate by moving
不管怎样，为了更好地利用可用的日光，我们通过把
our clocks forward one hour.
钟调快一小时来补偿。
I see.
我明白了。
That's convenient.
真方便。
I never understood things like this, such as GMT.
我从来不懂像GMT这样的东西。
I never know what time zone we are in or when to change my clock.
我总不知道我们在哪个时区，或者什么时候调钟。
That just stands for Greenwich Mean Time.
那代表格林威治标准时间。
Here in California, we're in Pacific Standard Time.
在加州这里，我们用的是太平洋标准时间。
That is eight time zones west of Greenwich.
那是格林威治以西八个时区。
Remember when we were in Beijing?
还记得我们在北京的时候吗？
Well, then we were in China Standard Time, and that's eight time zones east of Greenwich.
嗯，那时我们用的是中国标准时间，那是格林威治以东八个时区。
That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA, because of the huge time difference.
这就是为什么从北京飞到洛杉矶那么奇怪，因为时差很大。
Even though we left Beijing at noon and flew for more than eight hours, we still arrived
尽管我们中午离开北京，飞了八个多小时，我们还是
in LA the same day at noon.
在同一天中午到达洛杉矶。
It's like we went back in time.
就像我们回到了过去。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Now let's take a look at three key phrases in Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看流利度训练中的三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Let's go back to the beginning of this dialogue.
让我们回到这段对话的开头。
The person who's explaining all of these interesting things is saying that, well, in any case,
解释所有这些有趣事情的人说，嗯，不管怎样，
to take better advantage of the daylight available, we compensate by moving our clocks forward
为了更好地利用可用的日光，我们通过把钟调快
one hour.
一小时来补偿。
This is an important phrase you could say to take better advantage of or to take advantage
这是一个重要的短语，你可以说“to take better advantage of”或“to take advantage
of.
of”。
Let's talk about this.
我们来谈谈这个。
To take advantage of something.
利用某事物。
So to take advantage of something is to use it efficiently, right?
所以“利用某事物”就是高效地使用它，对吧？
Or to take better advantage.
或者更好地利用。
So for example, if you drive to work every day and your neighbor drives to work every
比如，如果你每天开车上班，你的邻居也每天开车上班，
day and you work at the same place, you could take better advantage of your car and the
而且你们在同一个地方工作，你们可以更好地利用汽车和
cost by sharing the same car to work.
成本，通过拼车上班。
Exactly.
没错。
Or when people started to use computers, you could say, well, they were taking better advantage
或者当人们开始使用电脑时，你可以说，他们通过加快速度、提高效率，更好地利用了
of their time by speeding things up, by making things faster with the computers.
他们的时间。
Right.
对。
Or many mothers say, take better advantage of your time and read something instead of
或者很多妈妈会说，更好地利用你的时间，读点书，而不是
playing those video games.
玩那些电子游戏。
Exactly.
没错。
So it means, like you said, to be more efficient, to do useful or important things.
所以它的意思就像你说的，更高效，做有用或重要的事情。
That's right.
是的。
And now when we talked about what daylight savings time means or GMT, what that stands
现在当我们谈到夏令时是什么意思，或者GMT代表什么时，
for.
This is an interesting phrase.
这是一个有趣的短语。
It stands for.
它代表。
Well, think about it as a picture.
嗯，把它想象成一幅画。
So if something stands for something else, that means the original thing, it's not there
所以如果某事物代表另一事物，那就意味着原来的东西已经不在了。
anymore.
And so in words and phrases like GMT, GMT doesn't mean anything by itself.
所以在像GMT这样的单词和短语中，GMT本身没有意义。
But the G stands for something, the M stands for something.
但G代表某物，M代表某物。
It's an acronym.
这是一个首字母缩略词。
Okay.
好的。
So this is an acronym that stands for, that represents three big long words.
所以这是一个首字母缩略词，代表三个很长的单词。
Okay.
好的。
Greenwich, meantime.
格林威治，平均时间。
Right.
对。
So we use this a lot when we are defining words or when we are defining an acronym like
所以我们在定义单词或定义像GMT这样的首字母缩略词时经常用到这个，
GMT stands for Greenwich, meantime.
比如GMT代表格林威治平均时间。
Or for example, USA stands for United States of America.
或者例如，USA代表美利坚合众国。
Or we can even say someone's name stands for something.
或者我们甚至可以说某人的名字代表某物。
So Marco, what is the M in your last name stand for?
所以Marco，你姓氏里的M代表什么？
So you're Marco M. What does the M stand for?
所以你是Marco M。M代表什么？
Right.
对。
And then I would say, well, it stands for Mejia.
然后我会说，嗯，它代表Mejia。
Your last name.
你的姓氏。
Right.
对。
And then we use this when you see things that you don't understand, maybe an acronym or
然后当我们看到不懂的东西时，比如一个首字母缩略词或
an abbreviation.
缩写，也会用到这个。
Like does Cathy stand for Catherine?
比如Cathy代表Catherine吗？
Yes, Cathy stands for Catherine.
是的，Cathy代表Catherine。
It's a short version of Catherine.
它是Catherine的简称。
Cool.
酷。
All right.
好的。
And well now talking a little bit more about time, you've maybe seen the movie Back to
嗯，现在再多谈一点时间，你可能看过电影《回到
the Future and this is what it's all about, to go back in time.
未来》，这就是它的主题，回到过去。
To go back in time.
回到过去。
So we went back in time.
所以我们回到了过去。
This is what the person says about the flight from Beijing to LA.
这是那个人关于从北京到洛杉矶的航班说的话。
What's interesting is that to go back in time is kind of a fixed phrase.
有趣的是，“回到过去”是一个固定短语。
We always say it like this.
我们总是这么说。
So we could say, if you went back in time, where would you go?
所以我们可以说，如果你回到过去，你会去哪里？
What time?
什么时间？
What place?
什么地方？
Right.
对。
So to go back in time, you usually use it like this.
所以“回到过去”通常这样用。
Now, what if I wanted to say to go into the future?
现在，如果我想说去未来呢？
Could you say, go forward in time?
你能说“向前到未来”吗？
You could go forward in time or you could go into the future.
你可以说“向前到未来”或“进入未来”。
Right.
对。
Go into the future.
进入未来。
So remember, if you want to talk about going back in time, it's usually traveling to the
所以记住，如果你想谈论回到过去，通常是指旅行到
past.
过去。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So that's all the phrases we have.
这就是我们所有的短语。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the very last time.
我们最后再听一遍对话吧。
Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time?
你为夏令时把钟拨快了吗？
What?
什么？
Why do we have to do that?
我们为什么要这么做？
Well, at the start of the spring, we usually have more daylight in the mornings and less
嗯，在春天开始时，我们通常在早晨有更多的日光，下午
in the afternoon.
较少。
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the earth.
这基本上是由于我们在地球上的位置和地球的自转。
In any case, to take better advantage of the daylight available, we compensate by moving
无论如何，为了更好地利用可用的日光，我们通过把
our clocks forward one hour.
时钟拨快一小时来补偿。
I see.
我明白了。
That's convenient.
那很方便。
I never understood things like this, such as GMT.
我从来搞不懂像GMT这类东西。
I never know what time zone we are in or when to change my clock.
我总搞不清我们在哪个时区，也不知道什么时候该调钟。
That just stands for Greenwich Mean Time.
那代表格林威治标准时间。
Here in California, we're in Pacific Standard Time.
在加州这里，我们用的是太平洋标准时间。
That is eight time zones west of Greenwich.
那是在格林威治以西八个时区。
Remember when we were in Beijing?
还记得我们在北京的时候吗？
Well, then we were in China Standard Time and that's eight time zones east of Greenwich.
嗯，那时我们用的是中国标准时间，那是在格林威治以东八个时区。
That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA, because of the huge time difference.
这就是为什么从北京飞到洛杉矶那么奇怪，因为时差太大了。
Even though we left Beijing at noon and flew for more than eight hours, we still arrived
尽管我们中午离开北京，飞了八个多小时，但我们还是
in LA the same day at noon.
在同一天中午到达洛杉矶。
It's like we went back in time.
就好像我们回到了过去。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Now, this is actually something that really does happen, right?
现在，这其实是真的会发生的事情，对吧？
If you take off in an airplane from Beijing, you fly for a certain amount of hours and
如果你从北京坐飞机起飞，飞了一定时间后
you reach California and it's still the same time.
到达加州，时间还是相同的。
You reach it in the same day.
你在同一天到达。
It's very strange.
这很奇怪。
The same thing happens to me when I go home.
我回家时也遇到同样的情况。
I leave Shanghai and I arrive in Chicago and I arrive at the exact same time I left on
我离开上海，到达芝加哥，到达的时间和我离开的时间完全一样，
the same day.
在同一天。
It's like time never passed.
就好像时间从未流逝。
It's the longest day of your entire life, because it's not 24 hours.
那是你一生中最长的一天，因为它不是24小时。
The flight is 14 hours.
飞行时间是14小时。
It's really 24, 38 hours long, right?
实际上有24、38小时那么长，对吧？
It's really intense and exhausting.
真的很累人，让人筋疲力尽。
Then what happens is when you do the opposite.
然后当你反向飞行时，情况就不同了。
You go from Chicago to Shanghai, then you go into the future pretty much, right?
你从芝加哥到上海，那差不多是进入未来，对吧？
Because you left on a Sunday, but you arrive on a Tuesday.
因为你周日离开，但周二才到达。
Or in my case, yeah, you leave on a Sunday and you'd arrive on a Monday and you lose
或者对我来说，是的，你周日离开，周一到达，你失去了
half a day of your life.
生命中的半天。
You're just sitting there and all of a sudden it goes past you.
你就坐在那里，突然时间就过去了。
So it all evens out in the end.
所以最终一切都扯平了。
So when you go back or when you come, it all evens out.
所以当你回去或过来时，一切都扯平了。
You recover, you get those hours of your life back pretty much.
你恢复过来，差不多把生命中的那些小时找回来了。
They're not gone forever.
它们不会永远消失。
All right.
好了。
So if you guys have any questions, any doubts, you can send us an email at EnglishPod at
所以如果你们有任何问题、任何疑问，可以发邮件到 EnglishPod at
PraxisLanguage.com or come to our website EnglishPod.com.
PraxisLanguage.com，或者访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你们。
Ask away and until next time everyone.
尽管提问吧，下次再见，各位。
Bye.
再见。